<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Nicko Hristov!</title>
    <link>https://nickohristov.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hi, I&#39;m Nicko Hristov!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 16:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nickohristov.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Secure Authentication</title>
      <link>https://nickohristov.de/posts/secure-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickohristov.de/posts/secure-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Passwords are old and boring New technologies! passwordless authentiacation
Deep dive explanation </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective search queries</title>
      <link>https://nickohristov.de/posts/search-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickohristov.de/posts/search-queries/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup file sharing with SMB</title>
      <link>https://nickohristov.de/posts/smb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickohristov.de/posts/smb/</guid>
      <description>Having hundreds of gigabytes and sometimes even multiple terabytes can get fastly very challanging for regular transfers and backups. Therefore we can make management very easy when instead using network storage, which only needs to be mounted on the corresponding machines. The following should serve as a cheatsheet for quickly setting up samba shares on the home network.
Install and setup samba $ sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt install samba For security disable Samba NetBIOS service, as we won&amp;rsquo;t use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GnuPG Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://nickohristov.de/posts/gpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickohristov.de/posts/gpg/</guid>
      <description>You have probably noticed that logo in the contact options on my landing page. That&amp;rsquo;s simply because as uniform and decentralized email is, it has one major flaw: At default it&amp;rsquo;s not end-to-end encrypted and therefore completely unsecure. GPG addresses exactly this problem by implementing the PGP (Pretty Good Privacy) protocol (pretty confusing naming scheme, I know ;) and offering asymetric encryption which is mostly used to ensure mail-conversation confidentiality and integrity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die RGBibel</title>
      <link>https://nickohristov.de/posts/rgbibel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickohristov.de/posts/rgbibel/</guid>
      <description>RGBote  Du sollst keine Apple Produkte kaufen. Mehr RGB, mehr FPS. Du sollst die RGB-Stripes ehren wie deine eigenen RGB-L체fter. Gaming PCs werden immer selber gebaut. Du sollst dich deiner Rainbow-Tastatur gleichstellen. Du sollst die 16,7 Millionen Farben ehren und kennen. Du sollst die deinesgleichen stets mit einem LED-Band beschenken. Kein Preis ist f체r eine gute RGB-Beleuchtung zu hoch. Der Threadripper ist kein Gaming-Prozessor. Eine Wasserk체hlung sollte stets gef채rbt sein.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
